CIPRIAN LAZAR

Senior Software Engineer

<u>+40 742 126 607</u>

<u>lazar.ciprian07@gmail.com</u>

Galati/Romania



Go enthusiast and experienced PHP Programmer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Self-discipline, committed, able to make right decisions in stressful and risky conditions of high stake projects and take full responsibility for them. Goal-oriented mind effective in finding new ideas and optimal solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IV Future Galati, RO Aug 2020 - Present

Aug 2020 - Present

Senior Developer/Team lead

Multitenant Marketing Application - Romania

Description: Multitenant marketing tool integrated with applications like Shopify and Medusa.js, enabling email campaigns, transactional emails, customer segmentation and template editing.

Impact: Improve client retention and engagement.

Team: Led 3 developers

Stack: NodeJs, NestJs, React, Redis, Shopify, AWS

Warehouse Management System (WMS) - Romania

Description: Cloud-based WMS integrated with Gomag, easySales, and MerchantPro, streamlining warehouse operations and real-time inventory management.

Impact: Increased turnover by automating processes and improving operational efficiency.

Team: Led 1 developers

Stack: PHP, Mysql, Redis, HTML/CSS/JS, RabbitMq, Symfony

Shop integration with Microsoft Xbox account POC - UK

Description: Integrated Microsoft Xbox accounts to retrieve in-game achievements for enhanced user shop experience.

Impact: Improved client retention and engagement by offering personalized gaming rewards.

Stack: NodeJs, MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JS, Bootstrap, Passport

Media library application - UK

Description: Media asset upload and processing platform handling images, videos, and documents, with print-on-demand features for image collage generation.

Impact: Reduced operational costs through automation of asset processing and order fulfillment.

Team: Led 2 developers

Stack: Golang, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Amazon S3, Keycloak, Kubernetes

Email Automation Platform - UK

Description: Multitenant email automation platform with segmentation, template customization and quota management, handling high-volume email marketing campaigns.

Impact: Improved client engagement by sending ~130K marketing emails in under 15 minutes.

Team: Led 2 developers

Stack: NodeJs, Golang, Mysql, FeathersJS, RabbitMq, Amazon S3, SendGrid, Keycloak,

Kubernetes

Application tools for Shopify merchants - UK

Description: Application suite to help Shopify merchants optimize customer acquisition and retention through a centralized CRM.

Impact: Improve customer retention and acquisition for Shopify merchants.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, Redis, HTML/CSS/JS, Laravel, Shopify, AWS

Custom WordPress integration and maintenance - UK

Description: Integrated WordPress with Zoho, performed security updates, and improved code performance.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML/CSS/JS, Wordpress

SKILLS

Technical

PHP/Laravel/Joomla/Wordpress

Golang

Javascript/React

Mysql/PostgresMongoDB/Redis

RabbitMQ

Keycloak

HTML/CSS

Professional

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Faculty of Computer Science, Galati 2002 - 2007

LANGUAGES

Romanian (Native)

English (Professional)

INTERESTS

Traveling

Puzzles

Running

Gaming

Senior PHP Developer

E-Commerce application for restaurants - Bucharest,

Description: E-Commerce application for restaurants, menu, orders and stock management

for clients like Citygrill, Nikosgreektaverna. Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML/CSS/JS, Laravel

Digital Marketing application - Romania, Cyprus

Description: Digital Marketing solution designed for restaurants and hotels, including

email/SMS/push campaigns and loyalty programs. Impact: Improve client retention and engagement.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, Redis, HTML/CSS/JS, Laravel, Amazon S3, Amazon SNS

goCaution AG Bern, Switzerland

| Nov 2016 - Ian 2018

PHP Developer/Team lead

Tenant/Landlord property managers application -Switzerland

Description: Property management system for tenant/landlord interactions, improving tenant experience and reducing administrative overhead.

Impact: Reduced onboarding time and manual processing.

Team: Lead 3 developers

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML/CSS/JS, Laravel

CRM application for house rental insurance -Switzerland

Description: House rental insurance system, covering payments and sales reporting.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML/CSS/JS, Joomla, Bootstrap

SC Activemall SRL Galati, RO

| May 2008 - Nov 2018

Web Programmer

CRM application for VOIP company - USA

Description: A comprehensive CRM system managing phone number acquisition, E911 provisioning, fax services, call statistics and billing.

Impact: Increased operational efficiency and reduced customer onboarding.

Stack: Golang, Mysql, Redis, PubNub

Newspaper redaction web application - RO

Description: Content writing, content validating, generate documents for DTP, generate reporting

Impact: Reduced time-to-publish, improved content quality through streamlined validation processes and reduced manual processing time.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Joomla

Newspaper small advertisement application - RO

Description: Web application for content creation, validation, and document generation for DTP purposes.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML, jQuery, Joomla

Web application register tape advertising - USA

Description: Application to manage ad uploads, testimonials, and shipment tracking for registered tapes.

Stack: PHP, Mysql, HTML, jQuery, Joomla